Falguni Vasoya

M-204, Air Castles Society, Near Alard Group of Institutes, Marunji, Hinjewadi, Pune - 411057. (m) +91 9960240328 falgunigajera37@gmail.com

RESUME SUMMARY

Experienced and accomplished in different skills with different role like delivering lecture in various pharma subjects as an Assistant Professor, successful delivery of research project as a Research Fellow and Medicine dispensing work as a Pharmacist. With different roles and responsibilities I carried out till today, I am having following various skills.

SKILLS

Analytical abilities : HPLC, HPTLC, UV

Teaching : Pharmaceutical Analysis, Biochemistry, Biopharmaceutics

Others : ADME studies, QA/QC, Dispensing of Medicine

Documentation : PCI, AICTE and ISO certification audit

EXPERIENCE

General Hospital, Sola, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India December 2013 – March 2015
 Pharmacist – Medicine dispensing, Stock management

2. B. V. Patel PERD Research Centre, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India September 2012 – July 2013 **Junior Research Fellow**

Project: "Pharmacokinetic study of Herbal Drugs" – This is achieved using ADME profile, *In-vitro* metabolism study using liver microsomes and Identification of metabolism using GCMS. Development of validation method is done using HPLC.

3. S. J. Thakkar Pharmacy College, Rajkot, Gujarat, India July 2008 – April 2012 **Assistant Professor**

Responsibility:

Lectureship in Biopharmaceutics, Biochemistry and Quality Analysis subjects Handling practical lab for Biochemistry and Quality Analysis subjects Guiding M.Pharm students for thesis work Preparing document for PCI, AICTE and ISO certification audit

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING

ESPEE Formulation Pvt. Ltd., Rajkot, Gujarat, India
 QC Trainee – Learned the different aspects of Tablet/Capsule manufacturing process and Quality control process.

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Aswatha Ram H. N.*, Shreedhara C.S., **Falguni P. Gajera** and Sachin B. Zanwar., *In Vitro* Free Radical Scavenging Potential of Methanol Extract of Entire Plant of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir", Pharmacologyonline, May-August 2008, Vol. 2, 440- 451.
- 2. Aswatha Ram H.N., Shreedhara C.S., **Falguni Gajera P.** and Sachin Zanwar B.,"Pharmacognostical Evaluation of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir." Pharmacognosy Magazine, Apr-Jun 2009, 4(18): 176-182.
- 3. **Gajera Falguni P.**, Movalia Dharmishtha A. and Gajera Keyur P., "Quantitation of Rutin in Methanolic Leaf Extract of *Phyllanthus reticulates* Poir. by High Performance Thin Layer Chromatography." international Journal of pharmacy research and development, July-2009 / Volume 1 / Article No 1.
- 4. Shreedhara C.S., Aswatha Ram H.N., Sachin B. Zanwar, **Gajera P. Falg**uni, "Free radical scavenging activity of aqueous root extract of *Argyreia nervosa* (Burm.f.) Boj. (Convolvulaceae)", Journal of Natural Remedies, July-Dec 2009, Vol. 9/2: 216-223.
- 5. **Gajera Falguni P.**, Movalia Dharmishtha A. and Gajera Keyur P., Development and Validation of HPTLC Method for Quantitative Estimation β-sitosterol in Plant Extract of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir. In international journal of pharmaceutical formulation and analysis, March-2010, Vol. 2.
- 6. Annie Shirwaikar, Saleemulla Khan, Yogesh H. Kamariya, Bharatkumar D. Patel and **Falguni P. Gajera**, Medicinal Plants for the Management of Post Menopausal Osteoporosis: A Review, The Open Bone Journal, 2010, 2, 1-13.
- 7. C.S. Shreedhara, H.N. Aswatha Ram, B. Sachin Zanwar and **P. Falguni Gajera**, "Medicinal Plants Possessing Anti-venom Activity--A Review", In: Indian Medicinal Plants, Edited by P.C. Trivedi, Aavishkar Publishers, Jaipur, 2009, pp 124-145.

EDUCATION

- M. Pharm (Pharmacognosy) with 80.00% (Distinction)
 MCOPS, Manipal University, Karnataka, India
 Thesis: Pharmacognostical, Phytochemical and Hypolipidemic activity of *Phyllanthus reticulatus Poir*.
- 2. **B. Pharm** with 71.31% (Distinction) April 2006 Rofel college of Pharmacy, Vapi, V.N.S.G.U, Surat, Gujarat, India
- 3. **H.S.C.** with 75.85% (Distinction) April 2002 G.S.H.S.E.B., Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India
- 4. **S.S.C.** with 85.86%. (Distinction) March 2000 G.S.E.B., Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

LANGUAGES

Gujarati - Native language Hindi and English - Speak fluently and read/write with good proficiency